Finding Aid for John and Leni Sinclair Papers 1957-2003
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sound Recordings
  - Sound reels
    - Interviews with, and speeches of, counter-culture figures [Unit II]
      - Discussion concerning John Sinclair while he was in prison; (Unit II, no. 36), 1971, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1036-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of discussion about John Sinclair and his time spent in prison.)
      - Stew Cox interviews with Archie Shepp on WDET; (Unit II, no. 37), 1971, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1037-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of Stew Cox interviewing Archie Shepp on WDET.)
      - Outtakes from John Sinclair radio special; (Unit II, no. 38), 1971, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1038-1]; mp3 file; (Includes Allen Ginsberg introduction of Sinclair, and Sinclair reading at the Berkeley Poetry Conference 1965, Leni Sinclair and David Sinclair speaking on drug arrests and sentencing.)
      - Interview with Dave and Leni Sinclair and Gary Grimshaw by Jesse Crawford; (Unit II, no. 39), [Undated, circa 1972], 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1039-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of Dave and Leni Sinclair interview on White Panther Party publications, John Sinclair's imprisonment )
      - Mike Brenner show on WRIF-FM with John Sinclair; (Unit II, no. 40), 1972 January 24, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1040-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of Mike Brenner show on WRIF-FM interviewing John Sinclair.)
      - Interview with Dave Sinclair concerning political history of Rainbow People's Party and its predecessors; (Unit II, no. 41), 1973 July 14, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1041-1]; mp3 file; (Interview discusses racism, anti-war and cultural revolution movements, Trans-Love Energies, and the Detroit Riot.)
        - [Part 2], [850-SR-1041-2]; mp3 file; (Interview discusses upcoming trial in Cadillac, MI with unidentified speaker, possibly Pun Plamondon?)
        - [Part 3], [850-SR-1041-3]; mp3 file; (Dave Sinclair discusses the formation of the White Panther Party.)
      - Talk show concerning Tribal Funding, Inc., represented by Frank Bach, Jeanie Plamondon and John Sinclair; (Unit II, no. 42), [Undated], 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1042-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of a talk show on WCBN about Tribal Funding Inc. and discussing Concert promotion in Ann Arbor and Washtenaw County.)
      - Community Comment talk show with John Sinclair concerning Tribal Funding, Inc.; (Unit II, no. 43), 1973 December 03, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1043-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of Communty Comment talk show with John Sinclair discussing Tribal Funding Inc.)
      - Patricia Hearst interview; (Unit II, no. 44), 1974 June 07, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 5 inch, 7 1/2 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1044-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of a interview with Patricia Hearst.)
        - [Part 2], [850-SR-1044-2]; mp3 file; (Tape content does not match original description; this portion of the tape only contains jazz music, no spoken content.)
      - Joilette Payne/Mary Rosenthal conversation labeled "The Dick Cavett of Oak Park"; (Unit II, no. 45), 1983 January 02, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1045-1]; mp3 file; (Discussion of racial identity and related issues.)
    - Free Park Concerts (Unit III)
      - "Full Tilt Benefit" rock concert music undated (Unit III, no. 46), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 31)
      - Ann Arbor Community Park Program on WNRZ-FM July-August 1972 (Unit III, nos. 47-49), 3 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 and 3 and 3 3/4 ips. 7 in. (Box 31)
      - Ann Arbor park concert performance of Radio King Band June 12, 1973 (Unit III, no. 50), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 31)
      - Deliverance, rock group, performance at the free park concert held at the Otis Spann Memorial Field June 24, 1973 (Unit III, no. 51), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 3-3/4 ips; 7 in. (Box 31)
      - Rock group "Truth" at Ann Arbor park concert June 24, 1973 (Unit III, no. 52), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 31)
      - Rock group Deliverance at a park concert July 8, 1973 (Unit III, no. 53), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in. (Box 31)
    - Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival performances (Unit IV)
      - Recording September 1972 (Unit IV, nos. 54-57), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 31)
      - Recording of Art Ensemble of Chicago group September 1972 (Unit IV, no. 58), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 31)
      - Female vocalist, Cocoa undated (Unit IV, no. 59), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 31)
      - Various performances undated (Unit IV, nos. 60-64), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 31)
      - General announcements followed by performance by Robert Junior Lockwood 1974 (Unit IV, no. 65), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in. (Box 31)
      - Recording 1974 (Unit IV, nos. 66-67), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in. (Box 31)
      - Performances include negro spirituals, such as "Amazing Grace," 1974 (Unit IV, no. 68), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in. (Box 31)
      - Various performances undated (Unit IV, nos. 69-73), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 in. (Box 31)
      - "Ann Arbor Boogie" recordings of various performances September 1973 (Unit IV, nos. 74-77), r audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 in. (Box 32)
      - "Detroit Blues" various artists' performances September 1973 (Unit IV, nos. 78-79), 2 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 in. (Box 32)
      - "Chicago Blues" various artist performances, undated (Unit IV, nos. 80-81), 2 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 32)
      - 1972 Recordings, various performances Unit IV, nos. 82-85), 4 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips. 7 in. (Box 32)
      - 1973 Recordings, various performances (Unit IV, nos. 86-90), 5 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips. 7 in. (Box 32)
      - Hound Dog Taylor September 1973 (Unit IV, nos. 91-92), 2 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 in. (Box 32)
      - Mighty Joe Young, September 1973 (Unit IV, no. 93, 94, 94a), 3 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 in. (Box 32)
      - Sun Ra September 1973 (Unit IV, no. 95), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 in. (Box 32)
      - Louis Spahn with Mighty Joe Young September 1973 (Unit IV, no. 96), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 in. (Box 32)
      - John Sinclair and Jim Dulzo discussing and playing cuts from the 1972 Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival LP May 1973 (Unit IV, no. 97-98), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 1-2 ips, 7 in (Box 32)
      - WDET Broadcast? of 1973 Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival, 1973 (Unit IV, no. 99), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 in (Box 32)
    - John Sinclair rallies (Unit V)
      - 10 for 2 soundtrack (from John Sinclair Freedom Rally, Ann Arbor) December 10, 1971 (Unit V, nos. 100-101), 2 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 32)
      - 10 for 2 soundtrack December 10, 1971 (Unit V, no. 102), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 10 in. (Box 32)
        (remastered July, 1981)
      - Free John Now rally, 1971 (Unit V, no 103), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 32)
        (labeled "first half")
    - Poetry performances, and recordings (Unit VI)
      - Poetry performances, and recordings: John Sinclair Selected Reading; (Unit VI, no. 104), 1964 November 22, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1104-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of John Sinclair reading his poetry.)
        - [Part 2], [850-SR-1104-2]; mp3 file; (Recording of John Sinclair in his home speaking over a variety of music.)
      - Poetry performances, and recordings: John Sinclair, Robin Eidele, George Tysh, Poets and Press Theatre Benefit; (Unit VI, no. 105), 1965, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7.5 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1105-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of a jazz music performance, no spoken content.)
        - [Part 2], [850-SR-1105-2]; mp3 file; (Poetry performances and recordings by English and Dana.)
      - Poetry performances, and recordings: John and David Sinclair reading; (Unit VI, no. 106), 1966, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1106-1]; mp3 file; (John and David Sinclair reciting poetry.)
      - Poetry performances, and recordings; John Sinclair (Unit VI, no. 107), 1969 Spring, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 5 inch, 7.5 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1107-1]; mp3 file; (John Sinclair reading "Rock and Roll is a Weapon of Cultural Revolution," with Bob Rudnick reading "Preview," and Pharaoh Sanders at end of reading.)
      - Poetry performances, and recordings: Allen Ginsberg, "Prayer for John Sinclair"; (Unit VI, no. 108-109), 1971 November, 2 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 5 inch, 7.5 ips
        - [Tape 1, Part 1], [850-SR-1108-1]; mp3 file; (Reel 1 of 2; Allen Ginsburg performing "Prayer for John Sinclair" at the "Free John Sinclair Concert.")
        - [Tape 2, Part 1], [850-SR-1109-1]; mp3 file; (Reel 2 of 2; Allen Ginsburg performing "Prayer for John Sinclair" at the "Free John Sinclair Concert.")
      - Poetry performances, and recordings: John Sinclair, Ed Sanders, Ken Mikolowski reading at University of Detroit; (Unit VI, no. 110), 1972, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7.5 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1110-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of Poetry readings by John Sinclair, Ed Sanders, Ken Mikolowski at the University of Detroit.)
      - Poetry performances, and recordings: John Sinclair, Jerry Younkins reading at the University of Michigan; (Unit VI, no. 111), 1972, 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7.5 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1111-1]; mp3 file; (Recording of Poetry readings by Jerry Younkins and John Sinclair at the University of Michigan.)
      - Poetry performances, and recordings: John Sinclair and his Blues Scholars, at Alvin's; (Unit VI, no. 112-113), 1985, 2 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7.5 ips
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1112-1]; mp3 file; (Reel 1 of 2; Selection of musical performances and poetry readings of John Sinclair and his Blues Scholars at Alvins.)
        - [Part 1], [850-SR-1113-1]; mp3 file; (Reel 2 of 2; Selection of musical performances and poetry readings of John Sinclair and his Blues Scholars at Alvins.)
    - Sinclair or Michigan related music performances
      - John Badanjek "Coleman Young" and other songs (Unit VII, no. 114), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 inch, 7.5 ips (Box 71)
      - Music by Sidney James Blair and Vision undated (Unit VII, no. 115), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 71)
      - Buddies in the Saddle, at Pretzel Bell, Ann Arbor August 29, 1972 (Unit VII, no. 116), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 3 3/4 ips. 7 in. (Box 71)
      - Carnal Kitchen at "Trust Busters Ball" Ann Arbor circa 1972-1973 (Unit VII, no. 117), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 3 3/4 ips., 7 in. (Box 71)
      - Ornette Coleman jazz music and PCC (People's Communication Committee) news dubs undated (Unit VII, no. 118), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in. (Box 71)
      - Deluxe, 5 songs November 1, 1974 (Unit VII, no. 119), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips, 7in. (Box 71)
      - Detroit, live and studio recordings (Unit VII, no. 120-124), 5 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 and 3 3/4 ips., 7 in (Box 71)
      - Electric Express, sickle cell anemia benefit, Flint August 31, 1973 (Unit VII, no. 125), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 71)
      - Flying Tigers, demos 1983 (Unit VII, no. 126), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 71)
      - Guardian Angel live and studio recordings, 1972 (Unit VII, no. 127), 5 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 71)
      - Infinite Sound (demo tape) 1973 (Unit VII, no. 128), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 71)
      - Lightnin, various live demo recordings and live performances 1972-1974 (Unit VII, nos. 129-133), 4 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 71)
      - Lightnin, various live demo recordings and live performances 1972-1974, 4 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 71)
      - Juanita McCray and her Motor City Beat, St. Andrews Hall. August 1983 (Unit VII, no. 134), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 71)
      - Scott Morgan "Soul Mover" and "Take a Look" (Unit VII, no. 135), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 71)
      - MC 5 recordings
        - MC 5 live at the Grande Ballroom May 26, 1968 (Unit VII, no. 136), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 15 ips, 7 in. (Box 71)
        - MC 5 live at the Union Ballroom September 23, 1968 (Unit VII, no. 137), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 71)
        - MC 5 live a the Grande Ballroom October 10, 1968 (Unit VII, no. 138), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips. 7in. (Box 71)
        - MC 5 and the Rationals live at the Grande Ballroom October 27, 1968 (Unit VII, no. 139), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 71)
        - MC 5 Back in the USA sessions July-August, 1969 (Unit VII, no. 140-142), 3 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips. 7 in. (Box 71)
        - MC 5 jam session, labeled "probably November 8, 9 1970" (Unit VII, no. 143), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 71)
        - MC 5 jam at Headsound Studios, Ypsilanti November 8, 1970 Unit VII, nos. 144-145, 2 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 72)
      - Mojo Boogie Band "Get Away" and "Go Home with You," November 4, 1974 (Unit VII, no. 146), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips. 7 in. (Box 72)
      - Mutants, various songs August 1974 (Unit VII, no. 147), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 72)
      - Jazz music, "Omnibus" December 1972 (Unit VII, no. 148), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 72)
      - Radio King and His Court of Rhythm, various live, demo, and studio recordings 1972-1975 (Unit VII, no. 148-155), 8 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 72)
      - Ramble Crowe, live WNRZ Sunday People's Concert undated (Unit VII, no. 156), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 in. (Box 72)
      - Rationals live at the Grande Ballroom circa October 27, 1968 (Unit VII, no. 157), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 72)
      - Spikedrivers, various songs, summer 1967 (Unit VII, no. 158), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in (Box 72)
      - Tate Blues Band, live at Otis Spawn Memorial Park, Ann Arbor June 24, 1973 (Unit VII, no. 159), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 72)
      - Terraplane, various songs June 21, 1973 (Unit VII, no. 160), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 72)
      - Unicorn News, sound collage of Democratic National Convention 1972 (Unit VII, no. 161), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 3-3/4 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 72)
      - The Up, various live, demo and studio recordings, 1969-1972 (Unit VII, nos. 162-180), 19 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 72)
      - The Urbations, various live, demo and studio recordings, 1982-1984 (Unit VII, no. 181-188), 8 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, primarily 7 /12 ips., 7 in. (Box 73)
    - Music related radio shows and promotional spots (Unit VIII)
      - WABX, "History of the Detroit Underground," radio show 1971-1972 (Unit VIII, no. 189), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 73)
      - WBCN, Ann Arbor, "Sister's Radio Show #1," 1972 (Unit VIII, no. 190), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 73)
      - WDET, Detroit, "Intro to Dizzy (Gillespie) concert," 1978 (Unit VIII, no. 191), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 73)
      - WEMU, Ypsilanti, John Sinclair and Michael G. Nastos 1981 (Unit VIII, no. 192), 3 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 73)
      - WGPR, Detroit, "Electrifying Mojo," November 26, 1981 (Unit VIII, no. 194), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips, 7 in. (Box 73)
      - WGPR, Detroit, "Electrifying Mojo," Spring 1982 and Duke-A-Paduka on WWOZ, Orleans, May 1982 (Unit VIII, no. 195), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips. 7 in. (Box 73)
      - WJLB, Rev. Pennington on WJLB December 24, 1977 (Unit VIII, no. 196), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips. 7 in. (Box 73)
      - WNRZ, Mock radio show proposal, October 31, 1970. (Unit VIII, no. 197), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 73)
      - WNRZ, Dr. John Interview December 12, 1972 (Unit VIII, no. 198), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in (Box 73)
      - WNRZ, "Toke Time with John Sinclair," March 26, 1973 (Unit VIII, no. 199), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 73)
      - "Weird Radio Air Checks and Debris," assembled 1981 (Unit VIII, no. 200), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 7 in. (Box 73)
      - Bob Rudnick Radio Spots, approximately 1969-1970 (Unit VIII, no. 201), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 15 ips., 7 in (Box 73)
      - Lightnin' spot for "WNRZ Marathon," approximately 1970-1972 (Unit VIII, no. 202), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7 in (Box 73)
      - People's Communication Committee "Takin Over" spot. (Unit VIII, no. 203), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 5 in. (Box 73)
      - WBCN spots (Music of Detroit, Various concerts) August 4, 1979 (Unit VIII, no. 204), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 5 in. (Box 73)
      - Miscellaneous spots 1972-1973 (Unit VIII, no. 205), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips. 5 in. (Box 73)
        ("Shots" promo with Bob Rudnick, Get out the Vote promo with Lightnin', Grande Ballroom benefit promos, "Bail Bond Boogie" promos) also includes The Up "Just Like an Aborigine" 45)
      - UMSOM spots for Concert December 7, 1979 (Unit VIII, no. 206), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips. 5 in. (Box 73)
      - Promo Spots (Music of Detroit and Jazz Development Workshop, Allied Artists Concert) August 4, 1979 (Unit VIII, no. 207), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips., 5 in. (Box 73)
      - Sample commercial spots produced by Rainbow Productions for promotional purposes and P.C.C. Michigan Boogie 1972-1973 (Unit VIII, no. 208), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 73)
      - Two commercial spots selling the 1972 Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival festival album, 1973 (Unit VIII, no. 209), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 4 in.; double track (Box 73)
      - WNRZ commercial spot advertising "Part III. The Music of John Coltrane," with John Sinclair and Dexter Q; and P.C.C. newscasts and election endorsements February 1973 (Unit VIII, no. 210), 1 audiotapes reel-to-reel tapes, 7-1/2 ips; 7 in.; double track (Box 73)
  - Compact discs, 26 optical disks CDs
    - Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival 1973
      - "Please Mr. Foreman": Motor City Blues (Box 73-A)
        (Volume 1)
      - Little Sonny: "Blues with a Feeling" (Box 73-A)
        (Volume 2)
      - "Grind It!" Roosevelt Sykes and Victoria Spivey (Box 73-A)
        (Volume 3)
      - "Well All Right! King Biscuit Boys/Big Walter Horton (Box 73-A)
        (Volume 4)
    - John Sinclair and His Blues Scholars
      - Full Moon Night (Box 73-A)
      - Full Circle (Box 73-A)
        (featuring Wayne Kramer)
      - White Buffalo Prayer (Box 73-A)
      - Steady Rollin' Man (Box 73-A)
        (John Sinclair and his Boston Blues Scholars)
    - John Sinclair and Ed Moss with the Society Jazz Orchestra
      - If I Could Be With You (Box 73-A)
    - John Sinclair
      - Underground Issues (Box 73-A)
      - Peyotemind (Box 73-A)
      - Various artists, 9 optical disks CDs (Box 73-B)
        (include MC-5; Rationals, The UP; Mitch Ryder)
  - Digital Audio Tapes (DATs)
    - Ann Arbor Blues and Jazz Festival 1974, 3 digital audio tapes (Box 73-B)
- Visual Materials
  The Visual Materials subgroup contains four series: Photograph, Posters and broadsides, etc, Videocassette and Videotapes.
  - Photographs
    The Photographs series consists of Sinclair personal and professional photographs including photos from the Artists' Workshop in Detroit, musical groups managed by Sinclair, and family photos; photograph files of newspapers Ann Arbor Sun and The Sun, published by Sinclair-related organizations, including photos of political activities in Ann Arbor and Detroit, Michigan (not confined to radical politics), musical events, particularly rock and jazz concerts, social activities including parades, festivals, and sporting events, and miscellaneous urban views; cartoon art from Ann Arbor Sun and The Sun newspapers; posters and broadsides, especially advertising rock and jazz concerts but also relating to political campaigns and campaign to legalize marijuana.
    - Sinclair personal and professional photographs
      (mainly black and white prints)
      - Pre 1978
        - Bach, Frank (Box 37)
        - Blues and Jazz Festival, Ann Arbor 1972, 1973 (Box 37)
        - Detroit Artists' Workshop period, 2 folders (Box 37)
        - Family (Box 37)
        - Hello and other publications (Box 37)
        - Human Rights Party, Ann Arbor, candidates (Box 37)
        - Musical groups
          - Deliverance (formerly 8th Day) (Box 37)
          - Detroit Band members (Box 37)
          - Lightnin' (Box 37)
          - MC 5 (Box 37)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 37)
          - Mojo Boogie Band (Box 37)
          - Sweet Jennie Grit (Box 37)
          - Three Bees Productions (Box 37)
          - Tribe (Box 37)
          - Up
            - Concert photos (Box 37)
            - Publicity poses (Box 37)
            - Miscellaneous (Box 37)
        - Perret, Christopher (Box 37)
        - Poets and writers (Box 37)
        - Rainbow Press (Box 37)
        - Sinclair, John and Leni (Box 37)
        - Translove Energies (Box 37)
        - Miscellaneous and unidentified (Box 37)
      - 1978-1999
        - Family photographs, 5 folders (Box 74)
          (includes wedding, 50th birthday and miscellaneous family photographs)
        - Performances
          - 1996 West Coast Tour (Box 74)
          - Performances, 1990s (Box 74)
          - Performances, 1970s-1980s (Box 74)
          - 3-D performance Photographs (Box 74)
        - Interviews/Public Appearances (Box 74)
        - Promotional photos/portraits and head shots
          - Portraits 1983 (Box 74)
          - Portraits 1988 (Box 74)
          - Miscellaneous 1980s (Box 74)
          - Miscellaneous 1990s, 2 folders (Box 74)
        - Ann Arbor News photo file (Box 74)
        - Musicians and performers
          - Eddie Jefferson (Box 74)
          - MC 5
            - Future/Now Films postcard sets (Box 74)
            - Wayne Kramer (Box 74)
          - Mitch Ryder (Box 74)
          - Miscellaneous musicians and performers (Box 74)
        - Autographed/Inscribed photographs WWOZ radio 1990s (Box 74)
        - Events
          - Detroit Jazz Center Opening 1979 (Box 74)
          - Radio Free Jazz Convention undated (Box 74)
          - Speaking Event with Sinclair, Rob Tyner, and others undated (Box 74)
          - Miscellaneous meetings and gatherings group photos undated (Box 74)